Guide to the Jack Lewis papers, 1915-2001.
Lewis, Jack papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Jack Lewis papers, 1915-2001.
6508
W. Jack. Lewis
51 cubic ft.
Printed material, correspondence, publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Personal and professional papers of Jack Lewis relating to his career as a chaplain and minister; the Christian Faith and Life Community; Cornell United Religious Work (CURW) and many community based social support programs.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Personal and professional papers of Jack Lewis relating to his career as a chaplain and minister; the Christian Faith and Life Community; Cornell United Religious Work (CURW) and many community based social support programs.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Lewis, W. Jack.; Cornell University Religious Work.
Subjects:
Clergy -- Ithaca.; College students -- Religious life.; Clergy.
Places:
New York (State) -- Ithaca
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Christian Faith and Life Community (CFLC) files
General Files
Administrative Files
Institute of Cultural Affairs (ICA)
Speaking Engagements and Conferences
Class, Program, and Workshop Papers
General Correspondence
Publications, Newsletters, and Bulletins
Series II. Cornell United Religious Works (CURW)
General Files
Administrative and Historical Files
Correspondence
Sage Chapel documents
Social Programs
Speaking Engagements, Workshops, and Conference Files
Resource Files
Series III. Work and Study Resource Files
Series IV. Social Programs
Alcoholism
Hospital Chaplaincy and Cornell Visitation
Pastoral Counseling
Cornell Retiree Program
Other Programs
Series V. Workshops, Lectures, and Sermons
General
Sage Chapel
Series VI. US Navy Documents
Alphabetical Correspondence Files
General Material
Funeral Services
Series VII. Series VII. Weddings (Restricted)
Series VIII. Series VIII. Funerals
Series IX. Personal Documents
Correspondence
General Materials
School Years
Travel
Series X. Publications
Series XI. Series Audio/Visual Material
CONTAINER LIST
- Christian Faith and Life Community (CFLC) files
  - Subseries Ia. General Files
    - CFLC history, 1950-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
      Includes brochures, correspondence, pamphlets, and building plans
    - CFLC first year history, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - CFLC history CH letters, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - CFLC history: beginning card file, 1953-1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - WJL: biographical sketch, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - WJL recommendations, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - WJL work papers collegium, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - CFLC publication testimonials, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Presbetery: general, 1954-1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Presbytery: the Texas Presbetary Foundation, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Presbytery of John Knox, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Presbytery of John Knox correspondence, 1966-1978 (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - Presbytery: Central Texas, 1953-1956 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Graham, Larry, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - General (requests for information), 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Concise interpretation on CFLC, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Religion and labor information, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Your heritage quote, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Resource material miscellaneous, 1953-1958 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Includes pamphlets, correspondence
    - Resource material: DRAMA, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
      A script for "The Sign of Jonah"
    - Resource: common worship working manual, Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - UT retreats correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - British Weekly articles, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - CFLC retreat manual material, 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - LUX withdrawal and return requests, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - LUX material file for future revision, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - What is Christian Worship?, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Tejas, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Church groups pamphlets and newsletters, Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Ecumenical education, Undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Log sheets and data on past calls, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - NY foundation data, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Prospects recently selected from WJL ancient notes, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - CFLC program for lay center, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - News releases, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - CFLC Women's branch, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      Includes copies of photographs.
    - College house retreat and services, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - College house, 1952-1963 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Worship service for retreat, 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 43-44)
    - Women's residence minutes, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Roll call and newsletters, 1952-1954 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - The Bentinck Island People's Story: a manuscript, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Summer housing, Peace Corps trainee program, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Layman's notebook, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
    - Lay centers in Europe, 1966-1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Lay centers in Europe, 1970-1979 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
    - Lay centers in the United States, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - The Dorm Situation paper, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - UT report on student counsel, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Ecumenical studies papers, 1960-1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Worship services, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Austin Ministerial Alliance, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - British Council of Churches pamphlets, 1951-1956 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Ecumenical Voluntary Project, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Ecumenical Work Camps, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Lay Centers U.S.A: Shadybrook House, Ohio, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - National Council of Churches, 1952-1960 (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
    - National Council of Churches: Department of Religious Liberty, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Quadrennial Convocation of Christian Colleges, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Religious Workers Association, UT area, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Southwest Ecumenical Institute, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Southern Methodist University Community House, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Student Christian Movement, Canada, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Tempo at Thompson House, Missouri, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Texas Council of Churches, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 28-29)
    - Texas Tech, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - United States Christian Movement, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Wisconsin, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - United Student Christian Council, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - World Council of Churches papers, 1955-1961 (Box 2, Folder 34-35)
    - World Council of Churches: Department of Laity, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 36-37)
    - World Student Christian Federation pamphlets, 1950-1959 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Yokefellow, 1954-1959 (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
    - CFLC Reunion, 1991- (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Notes and correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box 26, Folder 57-59)
    - Notes and correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - First Presbyterian Church Mason, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Westminster Presbyterian Church Austin, 1950-1959 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Associate program prospects, 1954 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Associate study course, 1954 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Helen Scott Salsbury bequest, 1982-1987 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Lay centers based on CFLC, 1950-1960 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Norman Elrod "On the Bad Mother", Undated (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - CFLC photographs, 1955-1965 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Waco, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - The association of Greek Christian doctors, Undated (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Pamphlets, publications, and notes, 1955-1963 (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Notes and newsletters, 1950-1960 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Task/time journals, 1961-1962 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Notebooks, 1950-1960 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - CFLC surveys on religion and politics in the community, 1954-1955 (Box 39, Folder 12-20)
      This material was heavily contaminated with mold and rat urine. Please use caution when handling.
    - CFLC surveys on religion and politics in the community, 1954-1955 (Box 40)
    - Slides and CFLC color film strip, 1955-1970 (Box 48)
    - CFLC scrapbook, 1953-1954 (Box 49)
    - CFLC scrapbook, 1955-1956 (Box 49)
    - CFLC scrapbook, 1957-1958 (Box 49)
  - Subseries Ib. Administrative Files
    - Prospects recently selected from WJL ancient notes, 1960-1962 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Donors, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Addresses, notes, and donors, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Donor lists and addresses, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Farm and Home savings and loans, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Donors, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Board meeting, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Notes, board papers, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - CFLC reports, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Associates Group initial memos presented to executive committee, 1954 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Board, 1963-11 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - CFLC: A Community of Learning in Theology and Culture, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 14)
      Includes board meeting and committee notes.
    - Report of the scholarship committee, 1952-09-1953-05 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Board of directors reports, 1963-1964 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Subseries Ic. Institute of Cultural Affairs (ICA)
    - Movies and TV requests for film, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - ICA correspondence, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Council on Religion and International Affairs, New York, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Church and State, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence and papers, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Social issues, 1960-1962 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Subseries Id. Speaking Engagements and Conferences
    - Speaking engagement refusals, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Speaking engagement refusals, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Past speaking engagements miscellaneous, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - WJL past speaking engagements: northeast, 1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - WJL past speaking engagements: southwest, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - WJL past speaking engagements: Texas, 1952-1960 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - WJL past speaking engagements: midwest, 1955-1960 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - WJL past speaking engagements: southeast, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - WJL past speaking engagements: south, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - WJL past speaking engagements: Europe (foreign), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      Includes three photographs of conference
    - American Lutheran Campus Pastors, 1962-04 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Peace conference, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Women's conference correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Speaking file: Holy Week services, Texas, 1962-04 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Future speaking engagements: Columbus group at Shadybrook, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Augustana College, Sioux Falls, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Nevada-Kansas City-St. Louis-Indianapolis-Pittsburgh, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Lutheran Evangelism conference, 1962-04 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Speaking engagements refused, 1959-1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - WCC Yale, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
    - Trips: past, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - WJL European trip, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Switzerland, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Australian trip study material, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Australian trip correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Australian trip and friends, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Talks, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Lake Forest College notes, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Subseries Ie. Class, Programs, and Workshop Papers
    - Curriculum Committee papers, 1953-1955 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Certificate of Commission, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Local church curriculum program file, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Parish Laymen's weekend seminar, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Religious education test, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Group work file set up 5163, Undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Self-evaluating point system, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Program films, purchase, and rental, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - The College House: Theological Studies II, IV, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - The College House: Community Studies I, II, III, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
    - The College House: Community Studies readings, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - The College House: Report, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - The College House surveys from former residents, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
    - The College House binder, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - The Laos House: Parish Laymen's advanced weekend seminar, community studies Ia, IIa, IIIa, Undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - The Laos House: working papers, 1958-1964 (Box 4, Folder 25-26)
    - The Laos House: weekend seminar, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - The Parish Ministers' Colloquy, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - University Under God, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Long Range Planning: The Presbyterian Ministry, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Lake Jackson, 1954 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Booklet for students, Undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Retreats, 1953 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      Includes fraternity retreat surveys.
    - Coursebook, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 15)
      Contains Laos House material.
  - Subseries If. General Correspondence
    - Charles M. Schulz, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Common worship, common study, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Center for the study of Democratic Institutions, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence to WJL, 1951-1962 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - CFLC letter draft from WJL, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence and notes, 1954-1959 (Box 5, Folder 10-12)
    - Correspondence received in absence, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Personal notes and correspondence, 1966-1977 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Subseries Ig. Publications, Newsletters, and Bulletins
    - Withdrawal and Return, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - LUX, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - CFLC services and newsletters, Undated (Box 5, Folder 17-18)
    - CFLC programs, newsletters, pamphlets, and publications, 1951-1961 (Box 5, Folder 19-23)
    - Letter to Laymen publications, 1956-1966 (Box 5, Folder 24-25)
    - Letter to Laymen policies, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Various pamphlets and CFLC publications, 1953-1963 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Various pamphlets and CFLC publications, 1950-1963 (Box 36, Folder 2-3)
    - Jack Lewis's leather folio with copies of CFLC publications, 1955-1963 (Box 47)
- Cornell United Religious Works (CURW)
  For other CURW related material, see Cornell Groups
  - Subseries IIa. General Files
    - Hilo Campus Ministry board meeting minutes and newsletters, 1975-1978 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Church and organization programs, 1970-1981 (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
    - Cornell Draft Information service, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Cynthia Chase, counselor, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Counseling: advice, counselings, and medical services, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Group counseling opportunities, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - New community information (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Rochester Council of Churches: Ministry of the Laity Communittee, 1964, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Volunteers in mission, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Adoption material, 1971-03 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Adoption material: Vogt-Marceau, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Ministerial data form, 1971-1974 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Conscientious objectors correspondence and information, 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Rite of Passage, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Tom Williams paper and correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Draft counseling sign up, Undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Middle East literature from Phil Bogdanoff, 1979-1981 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Mission of Cornell files, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 19-21)
    - Tickler file, Undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - ADFS 116, Erich Erikson memorandum on youth, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Human relations training group, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Division retreat: racism and alcoholism and sexism, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Cornell notes and correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Conseling helps, Undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Baccaloriat and commencement, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Plastic greenhouse plans, Undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Industrial Life Research and Development Center, Undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Mission Union Presbytery, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - VP candidates, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - ATH open house, 1971-09 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - World Out of Silence, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Interaction Exercise UN youth delegates, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Flood Relief Council, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Senate subcommittee, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Senate subcommittee on religious affairs, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 38-39)
    - Anabel Taylor general, 1964-1975 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Frank Rhodes inauguration, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - The Ecumenical Institute, 1968-1980 (Box 6, Folder 42-44)
    - WJL biography, Undated (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Lewis' performance evaluation, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - Bicentennial folder, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - Association of Cornell Emeritus Professors, 1983-1989 (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - Aerial photograph of central campus and photograph of Lewis at 1982 commencement, 1960-1982 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Photograph of Lewis and Daniel Berrigan, 1967-1970 (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - Articles and pamphlets on or by Daniel Berrigan, 1966-1974 (Box 31, Folder 5)
      Includes "The Great Berrigan Debate", "The World Showed Me It's Heart", and articles on the Middle East.
    - "Trial Poems" by Daniel Berrigan and Thomas Lewis, 1970
      Catalogued separately. Inscribed by Berrigan to Jack Lewis.
    - CURW and Cornell notes and publications, 1965-1975 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Subseries IIb. Administrative and Historical Files
    - CURW logo design: Sacred Design Associates, Inc., 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 46)
      Includes mockups of designs.
    - Papers on CURW, Undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Reorganization committee, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Meeting notes, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Campus budgets, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - The Great Berrigan Debate booklet, 1974-01 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Cooperative Religion at Cornell University booklet, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Our CURW Heritage booklet, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - CURW annual reports, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - CURW annual reports, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - CURW annual reports, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - CURW annual reports, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - CURW annual reports, 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - CURW annual reports, 1974-1978 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - CURW annual reports, 1978-1980 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - CURW annual reports, 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - CURW annual reports, 1982-1984 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - CURW annual reports, 1984-1986 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - CURW annual reports, 1986-1988 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Proposal for Restructuring CURW, 1970-03-09 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Kenneth Clark CURW director candidate interview packet, 1998-2002 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Subseries IIc. Correspondence
    - General correspondence, 1965-1969 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - General correspondence, 1966-1981 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - General correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 7, Folder 16-17)
    - General correspondence, 1972-1981 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - General correspondence, 1974-1980 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - General correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - General correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Ernst Bangs, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Personal correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Sensitive letters, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Cornell job correspondence, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Anderson, Laurie, 1967-11 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Counselee file: Rolley, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Dietrich, Joshua, 1973-07-1973-11 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Johnston, Peter, 1974-08 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Wallace, Julia, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - First Class Mail file, 1971-1980 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Notes and correspondence, Undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Welch, George, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Hoover, John, 1972-1977 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Scherer, John, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Wolfe, Hawley, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Thank you letters, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - CURW, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Presbytery del Salvador, 1972-1981 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - General correspondence, 1964-01-1964-06 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Includes photograph of Caragonne family and congratulatory letters on accepting CURW position.
    - General correspondence, 1969-1972 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and desk notes, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Desk notes and memos, Undated (Box 8, Folder 7-9)
    - General personal correspondence, 1968-1980 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - United Church of Canada, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Dale R. Corson, 1973-1975 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Anne Bell file, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Epistle from George Welch, 1975-04-01 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      Typed on the back of Vin Garbutt performance posters.
    - Retirement letters, 1981-02-1981-04 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Tompkins County Religious Workers Association, 1981-01 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Tompkins County Hospital, 1980-12 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Leonardo da Vinci Society, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Subseries IId. Sage Chapel Documents
    - Clippings and bulletins, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Readings, 1962-1972 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Advisory Council, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Sermon materials, Undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Files on Sage Chapel refurnishing and renovation, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 23-27)
      Includes correspondence, pamphlets, and reference photographs.
    - Sermon bulletins, 1966-1972 (Box 8, Folder 28-34)
      Many have notes and annotations by Lewis.
  - Subseries IIe. Social Programs
    Other CURW-related social programs may be under Series …. Social Programs
    - Suicide Prevention and Crisis Counseling introduction, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Suicide Prevention and Crisis Counseling, 1967-1983 (Box 9, Folder 2-7)
      Includes correspondence, board meeting minutes, calendars, and program information
    - Suicide Prevention training, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Suicide Prevention and Crisis Services fifteenth anniversary, 1984-04 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      Correspondence and notes
    - Suicide Prevention and Crisis file, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Suicide Prevention and Crisis Services evaluation, Undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Suicidal Phenomena: Their Definition and Classification, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      By Edwin Shneidman, with clippings
    - Alcoholism Council, 1968-1976 (Box 9, Folder 13-14)
      Includes correspondence, board meeting minutes, and program information
    - Interim Families Committee, Undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Battered women, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Rape Crisis Center, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Campus bridge safety proposals, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Fraternity Retreats, 1979-09 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Eco-justice funding proposals, Undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Clergy Consultation Service, 1969-1973 (Box 9, Folder 21)
      Includes program information on abortion, clippings, blank surveys, and publications.
    - Clergy Consultation Service correspondence and notes, 1969-1973 (Box 50, Folder 2-3)